A Guide to the George H. Hager Account Books, 1913-1925
Special Collections and University Archives, Virginia Tech
Special Collections and University Archives, Virginia Tech
George H. Hager Account Books, 1913-1925
Special Collections and University Archives, Virginia Tech, Blacksburg, Va.
Ms1940-013
1 Cubic Feet; 2 boxes
This collection contains account books, including customer account ledgers and order books, of George H. Hager, proprietor of a Wythe County, Virginia general mercantile store.
Hager, George H.
Administrative Information
Conditions Governing Access
The collection is open for research.
Source of Acquisition
The George H. Hager Account Books were transferred to the University Libraries in 1939 or 1940 and transferred to Special Collections and University Archives in 1955.
Biographical Note
The 1900 census describes George H. Hager as a 46-year-old Wythe County, Virginia farmer, living with his wife of 19 years, 40-year-old Ella Hager. According to the census record, George Hager was born in Virginia in January, 1854; Ella, in July, 1859. The couple had no children. The Hagers appear again in the 1910 census as farmers in Wythe County's Fort Chiswell District. In the 1920 census, George H. Hager is described by the census as a 66-year-old, Virginia-born department store merchant, living in Fort Chiswell with 59-year-old wife Ellie. The couple also appears in the 1930 census, the only change being their respective ages. The census of 1880 indicates that George H. Hager was the son of Wythe County residents John and Mary Hager.
Scope and Content
This collection contains account books of George H. Hager, proprietor of a Wythe County, Virginia general mercantile store. The collection includes 14 account ledgers in which Hager recorded customer names, the dates of transactions, goods purchased, and prices. Also included are two order books, which include lists of goods ordered and from whom ordered. The first of these, spanning the years 1913 to 1917, also seems to include customer account records from 1913. The second order book, covering 1918 to 1921, also contains Hager's accounts of money deposited and store expenses from 1913 to 1921. The books have all been rebound, with each cover bearing Hager's name and the town name of Gunton Park, Virginia. Also on each cover are the dates spanned by the book and sequential number (several of these dates and numbers are incorrect, however).
Arrangement
The collection is arranged by ledger type, then chronologically.
Rights Statement for Archival Description
The guide to the George H. Hager Account Books by Special Collections and University Archives, Virginia Tech, is licensed under a CC0 (https://creativecommons.org/share-your- work/public-domain/cc0/).
Index Terms
Subjects:
Account books; Local/Regional History and Appalachian South; Wythe County (Va.)
Contents List
- Account ledger, 1913-1914 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Account ledger, 1914 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Account ledger, 1914-1915 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Account ledger, 1915 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Account ledger, 1915-1916 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Account ledger, 1916 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Account ledger, 1919 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Account ledger, 1920 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Account ledger, 1920 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Account ledger, 1920-1921 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Account ledger, 1921-1922 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Account ledger, 1922-1923 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Account ledger, 1923 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Account ledger, 1924-1925 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Order book, 1913-1917 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Order book, 1918-1921 (Box 2, Folder 8)